https://slama.dev/comeback/
https://slama.dev/comeback/
In honor of the visit of Pope Benedict XVI to the Czech Republic, we are replacing the originally planned sinful dance with the suffering of Christ.
Na počest návštěvy papeže Benedikta XVI. v České republice zařazujeme místo původně plánovaného hříšného tance umučení Krista.
Enjoy the show.
Hezkou zábavu.
Ivo!
Ivo!
Tragedy.
Tragédie.
Did they raise the price of cocoa?
Zdražili kakao?
Don't make light of it.
Ty nezlepšuj to.
The building manager called a residents' meeting.
Správcová svolala domovní schůzi.
Oh no, is there already an agenda?
A je, je už i program?
Yeah.
No.
First.
Za prvé.
Installation of a gate in the basement to prevent hooligans from greasing the stairs with soap.
Pořízení mříže do sklepa, aby bylo chuligánům zamezeno natírat schody klouzkem.
Second.
Za druhé.
Installation of safety barriers to prevent unauthorized sliding of hooligans down the banister.
Instalace bezpečnostních zarážek pro zamezení nepovoleného sjíždění chuligánů po zábradlí.
Third, purchase of chains for the trash cans, so hooligans can't keep moving them in front of the building manager's door.
Za třetí, nákup řetězů k popelnicím, aby je chuligáni nemohli opakovaně stěhovat před dveře správcové objektu.
Fourth, the problem of rat infestation in the building manager's basement.
Za čtvrté, problém přemnožení potkanů ve sklepě správcové objektu.
You know what this means?
Víte, co to znamená?
34 points, Ozzak.
34 bodů, Ozzák.
Did you know that rats love cracklings?
Věděli jste, že potkani milují škvarky?
Ozzak is pulling pranks.
Ozzák dělá fórky.
The building manager is going to take away our basement, I can feel it in my bones.
Správcová nám sebere sklep, já to cítím v kostech.
She won't.
Nesebere.
She already took it from us once.
Už nám ho jednou sebrala.
But she gave it back.
Ale zase nám ho vrátila.
We have it on probation.
Máme ho podmíněně.
Jesus, where will we put the cranberries?
Ježišmarja, kam dáme klikve?
How about we finally throw them out after ten years?
Že bysme je po těch deseti letech konečně vyhodili?
Come on, Ivuska, you know I'm saving them for your wedding.
Tak Ivuško, víš, že je schovávám na tvou svatbu.
There's no wedding without a cranberry cake.
Bez klikvovýho dortu není veselka.
I hope I'm a lesbian.
Doufám, že jsem lesba.
What?
Cože?
That it's great.
Že je to bezva.
Yeah.
No.
What's gotten into Ozzak?
Co to do Ozzáka vjelo?
Why is he acting up?
Proč tak vyvádí?
He's just happy, you know.
Tak je veselej, no.
He finally found a good pub, so he's happy.
Našel si konečně dobrou hospodu, tak je šťastnej.
Happy, happy.
Šťastnej, šťastnej.
But why does everyone around have to be miserable because of his pranks?
Ale proč mají být kvůli jeho fórkům nešťastný všichni okolo?
Lebrajka, come here, come here.
Lebrajka, pojď sem, pojď sem.
We need to talk.
Musíme si promluvit.
Fine, but don't drag it out, I'm heading to the pub.
Fajn, ale moc to nerozjížděj, razím do hospody.
And what about the first three points?
A co ty první tři?
Well, Satan isn't around the corner.
No, Satan není za rohem.
Can't you pick a pub that's actually in Prague?
To si nemůžeš vybrat nějakou hospodu, která je v Praze?
But Satan is in Prague.
Vždyť Satan je v Praze.
Haje is technically East Prague, but I don't go there much.
Háje jsou sice už Praha východ, ale tam moc nechodím.
So you'll get home again only tomorrow?
Takže dorazíš domů zase až zejtra?
Today I'm getting a ride.
Dneska jedu fárem.
Ziza will drive me.
Žíža mě odveze.
Ziza has a car?
Žíža má auto?
Sure, a company vehicle.
No jasně, služebák.
We just have to make a stop at two septic tanks on the way.
Akorát se cestou ještě musíme stavit u dvou septiků.
Is that some kind of pub too?
To je taky nějaká hospoda?
No, she's got a sewage truck.
Ne, ona má hovnocuc.
Look, bro, I was gonna wait in front of the building, but the valve is tight, so it can't sit too long anywhere.
Ty hele brácha, já jsem myslel, že budu čekat před barákem, on je těsnej ventilek, tak nesmí nikde stát moc dlouho.
So get going.
No tak běž.
Did you get rid of that rat?
Toho potkana si vyhodil?
Sure, exactly as you said.
Jistě, přesně jak jsi říkal.
Anywhere, just not in the building manager's basement.
Kamkoliv, jenom ne ke správcový do sklepa.
Great.
Bezva.
In Vojtickova's basement.
K Vojtíčkový do sklepa.
She always goes down there at three to get her rice.
Vždycky ve tři si tam chodí pro rýži.
Are you out of your mind?
Ty jsi se zbláznil?
Mrs. Vojtickova is in cahoots with the building manager.
Vždyť ta paní Vojtíčková je se správcovou jedna ruka.
But even more shrill than the building manager.
Ale pištivější než správcová.
See, you could set your watch by her.
Vidíš, mohl bys podle ní řídit hodinky.
Ozzak, please, do you realize that because of your Canadian pranks we could end up in serious trouble? Watch out for Vojtickova.
Ozzáku, prosím tě, uvědomuješ si, že kvůli těm tvým kanadským žertíkům se můžeme dostat do strašného průšvihu? Na Vojtíčkovou bacha.
It's fine with Vojtickova.
S Vojtíčkovou je to v pohodě.
I didn't want to say it, but she's hitting on me.
Já jsem to nechtěl říkat, ale ona mě balí.
What?
Co?
But she's seventy.
Vždyť jí je sedmdesát.
Old wood burns the best.
Starý poleno nejlíp hoří.
Uncle.
Strejdo.
Aren't you confusing her with someone?
Nepleteš si ji s někým?
Vojtickova is the old lady who calls you a Satanist.
Vojtíčková, to je ta stará paní, co ti říká satanáši.
That's what I'm saying, I drive her crazy.
To povídám, šíleně ji rajcuju.
Every time she sees me, she grabs her chest.
Vždycky, když mě potká, tak si sahá na kozy.
What?
Cože?
I mean...
Totiž.
Jesus.
Ježišmarja.
But she doesn't stand a chance with me, she listens to funk.
Ale u mě nemá šanci, poslouchá funk.
Funk?
Funk?
Yeah, she keeps writing to me about trumpets.
No, pořád mi píše o trumpetách.
Bro, do you happen to have one of those letters here?
Brácha, nemáš náhodou tady nějaký ten dopis?
Yeah, but Ivuska shouldn't read it.
Jo, ale Ivuška by to číst neměla.
The old hag has no shame.
Bába nemá zábrany.
Devil's spawn.
Ďáblův z plozenče.
She knows how to get to me.
Ta ví, jak na mě.
Living under the same roof with you is hell.
Žít s tebou pod jednou střechou je peklo.
Whenever I see you, I pray that the time for God's judgment has finally come.
Kdykoliv tě potkám, modlím se, aby už konečně nastal čas božího soudu.
If it weren't for the funk, Sheldon.
Nebejt toho fanku, šéldoni.
Then the sinners shall be scorched by the fires of hell, but the righteous shall hear the trumpets of angels.
Tehdy hříšníky sežehne žár pekelný, ctní však uslyší trouby andělské.
That'll be Zizak.
To bude Žížák.
Tomas?
Tomáši?
Sorry, Marcelka, I had to go back to the building for galoshes.
Promiňte, Marcelko, musel jsem se vrátit do domu pro galoše.
Why?
A proč?
Ziza was waiting for Ozzak a bit too long.
Žíža čekala na Ozzáka asi moc dlouho.
Ugh!
Fuj!
Now I'm not surprised the whole east side didn't smell a thing.
Teď už se nedivím, že jsem vychodně nepáchla ani noha.
But on the radio they said it's supposed to rain tonight.
Ale v rádiu hlásili, že má v noci pršet.
If only.
Kéž by.
Ugh!
Fuj!
I always fall for it.
Až já mu na to vždycky skočím.
Ozzak won't get me.
Na mě si Ozzák nepřijde.
I'm careful now.
Už si dávám pozor.
After that neoprene on the toilet seat, I'll never sit down for his tricks again.
Od toho neoprénu na záchodovým prkýnku už mu naletět nesednu.
The register and the accounts are in the cash box.
Tržbu s vyúčtováním máte v kase.
Marcelka, wait!
Marcelko, moment!
I'm rushing to Zoran.
Já spěchám za Zoranem.
He's getting baptized and forgot his towel.
Dává se pokřtít a zapomněl si ručník.
Zoran?
Zoran?
Well, otherwise the Pope wouldn't receive him.
No, jinak by ho papež nepřijal.
The Pope is supposed to receive Zoran?
Zorana má přijmout papež?
He's giving him a private audience.
Poskytne mu soukromou audienci.
And you didn't say anything?
A že jste nic neřekla?
Well, I didn't want to jinx it.
No, tak nechtěla jsem to zakřiknout.
Zoran has been trying for a really long time.
Zoran se o to snaží už hrozně dlouho.
It's an exceptional honor.
Je to výjimečná pocta.
Even the mayor couldn't manage it at all.
Třeba takovému primátorovi se to nepodařilo vůbec.
And Zoran is, you know...
A Zoran je jako to?
A believer?
Věřící?
He will be, once I bring him that towel.
Bude, až mu donesu ten ručník.
Don't worry, he's only doing it so his herbal liqueur sells better in Sibenik.
Nebojte, dělá to jenom proto, aby se v Šibeniku líp prodával jeho bylinný likér.
Wait, I don't understand at all.
Počkejte, já vám vůbec nerozumím.
Zoran gets his photo taken with the Pope, puts it on the bottle, and Benedictinka will sell like hotcakes.
Zoran se nechá s papežem vyfotit, tu fotku dá na lahev a Benediktinka půjde na dračku.
Benedictinka?
Benediktinka?
New name.
Nový název.
It used to be called Sluze Franje Tudman and before that Tito's Bitter.
Dřív to byly Sluze Franje Tuđmana a předtím Titova Hořká.
Zoran says the Pope sells better today than sex and the Olympics combined.
Zoran říká, že papež dneska prodává líp než sex a olympiáda dohromady.
Maybe in Croatia, but here...
Možná v Chorvatsku, ale tady...
Well, you'd be surprised.
No, tak to byste se divil.
Check out the charts.
Mrkněte na hitparádu.
All the major Czech artists already figured it out.
Všichni významní čeští umělci už to pochopili.
What?
Co?
Number one, Maxim Turbulenc?
První Maxim Turbulenc?
I've Got Jesus in My Belly?
Mám v břiše Ježíše?
And look further down.
No a podívejte se dál.
Kabat.
Kabát.
Yeah, Kabat.
No jo, Kabát.
God Rode a Goat.
Bůh na koze jel.
And in third place, the Nedveds.
A na třetím místě Nedvědi.
Amen Means Amen.
Na amen je amen.
And then all the way to tenth place, nothing but religious stuff.
A pak až do desátého místa samý Šmožek.
People are buying it like crazy.
Lidi to kupujou jak šílený.
So why didn't you just order some right away?
No tak proč jste rovnou něco neobjednala?
Unfortunately, I can't open the supplier list.
Bohužel, nemůžu otevřít seznam dodavatelů.
How come?
Jak to?
Ozzak sprinkled sneezing powder on it.
Ozzák ho posypal kýchacím práškem.
Jesus, the towel.
Ježiš, ten ručník.
Marcelka, I promise I'll put a stop to his stupid pranks.
Marcelko, já slibuju, že mu ty jeho blbý fórky zatrhnu.
In a surprising move, the mayor urged Praguers to turn to God and announced he would be baptized immediately.
V překvapivém vystoupení primátor vyzval Pražany, aby se obrátili k Bohu a oznámil, že se okamžitě dává pokřtít.
He dismissed speculation that he plans to run in the South Moravian region as blasphemy.
Domněnky o tom, že hodlá kandidovat v jihomoravském kraji, označil za rouhání.
Ivo, drop everything, meeting.
Ivo, všeho nech, porada.
The building manager has the list of residents.
Seznam partají má správcová.
But I outsmarted her.
Ale já jsem na ni vyzrál.
I went around the doorbells.
Obešel jsem zvonky.
Wow, that's really clever.
Ty, to je fakt chytrý.
Why did you take such a risk?
Proč jsi tak riskoval?
Ivo, if there's going to be a vote about our basement, we need to secure support across the building.
Ivo, jestli se bude hlasovat o našem sklepě, musíme si zajistit podporu napříč partajima.
So, which one is Pajerova?
Takže, která je Pajerová?
Wait, you don't know everyone in our building?
Počkej, ty neznáš všechny lidi od nás v baráku?
No, I only really know Simona and the people who come to the shop to complain.
Ne, já znám dobře akorát Simonu a ty, co si chodí stěžovat do krámu.
So you know everyone.
No takže znáš všechny.
And did you get into it with Pajerova?
A s Pajerovou ses poštípal ty?
Me?
Já?
Come on, I never argue.
No dovol, já se nikdy nehádám.
Until someone tells you off for putting glass in the plastic bin.
Dokud ti někdo nevyčte, že házíš sklo do plastu.
Yeah, that's still a thing.
Jo, tohle furt je.
Okay, look at it, is there anyone on our side, anyone who kind of likes us?
Dobře, podívej se na to, je tam někdo na naší straně, ten je trošku rád.
Roubal.
Roubal.
Great, I'll go see him.
Bezva, jdu za ním.
That won't help, he mostly likes me and Sasa.
To nepomůže, ten má rád hlavně mě a Sašu.
Next.
Dál.
Podrouzek, he likes Lexa.
Podroužek, ten zas má rád Lexu.
Well, you know.
No víte.
But who knows if he hasn't gone off on a Scout hike again.
No ale kdo ví, jestli zase neodjel se scoutem na pochod.
This is hopeless.
To je bída.
If only Simona could be there.
Kdyby tam mohla být aspoň Simona.
But she's not allowed.
Vždyť ona tam nesmí.
No.
Ne.
The building manager banned her for two years for unauthorized termination of a meeting.
Správcová ji na dva roky vyloučila za neoprávněné ukončení schůze.
How unauthorized?
Jak neoprávněné?
When things were at their worst, she blew the fuses and screamed "watch out, a monitor lizard!"
Když tam bylo nejhůř, vyhodila pojistky a zařvala bacha varan.
Since then she has to vote by mail.
Od té doby musí hlasovat korespondenčně.
That door handle.
Ta naklice.
I'm going to lose my mind.
Já se z toho zblázním.
Yeah, his Canadian pranks are driving me nuts too.
Jo, z těch jeho kanad taky hrabe.
Last night I dreamed he woke me up and tried that trick with the telescope and the soot on me.
V noci se mi zdálo, že mě probudil a zkusil na mě ten trik s dalekohledem a sazema.
Ivuska, when you go to the bathroom, don't look in the mirror.
Ivuško, až půjdeš do koupelny, tak si nedívej do zrcadla.
I already did, yeah?
Já už jsem malá, jo?
Where did this come from?
Kde se to tu vzalo?
It was under the door.
Bylo to pod dveřma.
Oh my God.
Panebože.
Last night, hooligans stole a bench from the courtyard and the spare ficus from the landing.
Dnes v noci chuligáni odcizili lavičku ze dvora a záložní fíkus z mezipatra.
The hooligans and those who harbor them face exemplary punishment.
Chuligány i ty, kdo je přechovávají, čeká exemplární trest.
This is like under Heydrich.
To je jak za Heydricha.
Why does she want to take our basement?
Proč nás chce připravit o sklep?
She's old and bitter.
Je stará a zahořklá.
I mean Ozzak. It couldn't have been him.
Myslím Ozzák. To nemohl být on.
What would he do with a bench and a ficus?
Co by dělal s lavičkou a fíkusem?
Christ, how would I know?
Víš, Ježišmarja, co já vím?
Same thing he did with the geranium pots, the brooms, and the lids from Hajek's vacuum cleaner.
To, co udělal s pelargoniovými hrnci, smetáčky a puklicemi od Hajkova vysavače.
Candles?
Svíčky?
Or the slide, whatever.
Nebo skluzavku, to je jedno.
What are you doing?
Co to děláš?
I need to sweeten my life.
Potřebuju si osladit život.
That's salt.
A to je sůl?
Ivo, please, wake up.
Ivo, prosím tě, probuď se.
Glue on the door handles, tied shoelaces, a volleyball.
Pasta na klice, svázaný tkaničky, vodboj.
He definitely swapped the sugar and salt.
Určitě prohodil cukr se solí.
He did.
No prohodil.
Well, there you go.
No tak vidíš.
I already swapped them back.
Já už to vyměnila.
Hi.
Ahoj.
Hey, why so early?
Čau, co tak brzo?
Could I have breakfast at your place? Mom took away the table and I don't like eating on the floor.
Nemohla bych se u vás nasnídat? Maminka odnesla stůl a já nerada jím na zemi.
Sure.
Jasně.
Good morning.
Dobrý ráno.
Hi.
Ahoj.
Where's Lexa?
Kde je Lexa?
He's in the bathtub.
Ten přece je ve vaně.
Sasa, where did your mom take the table?
Sašo, a kam maminka odnesla stůl?
Probably where she put the couch and the carpet, to the resting room.
No, asi tam co pohovku a koberec, do odpočívárny.
The resting room?
Do odpočívárny?
Mm, Mom says things also need to rest when they've served for a long time.
Hm, maminka říká, že věci si taky musí odpočinout, když dlouho slouží.
That's sad.
To je smutné.
Why?
Proč?
Sasa, they'll come back good as new.
Sašo, vrátí se a budou jako vyměněné.
So, Sasa, how is your mom actually doing?
No, Sašo, a jak se vlastně má máma?
Since she lost her job, she's completely stopped going out.
Od té doby, co je bez práce, tak nám úplně přestala chodit.
Well, she didn't go anywhere for a long time because she can't stand people feeling sorry for her.
No, ona dlouho nechodila nikam, protože nesnáší, když ji lidi litujou.
But now that the sisters are going through Croatia, climbing into the tunnel every night, she's in a much better mood.
Ale co teďka sestry jdou Chorvátem, lezou každou noc do tunelu, tak má o moc lepší náladu.
What tunnel, for God's sake?
Do jakýho tunelu, proboha?
I asked her that too, she said curious children lose their ears.
To jsem se jí ptala taky, říkala, že zvědavým dětem upadnou uši.
Right.
No.
Cocoa gives me hives.
Po kakau je kopřivka.
Mom says, right?
Říká máma, co?
Yeah.
No.
Risk it.
Tak to riskni.
Good day.
Dobrý den.
Praise be.
Pochválen.
What are you playing?
Co to pouštíte?
Christian band Lazari.
Křesťanská skupina Lazaři.
Where did you get all this overnight?
A kde jste to přes noc všechno sehnala?
I found a company called God's Emergency Services.
Našla jsem firmu Boží pohotovost.
24 hours a day, except Sundays, Easter, Christmas, Pentecost, and the feast of Blessed Hroznata.
24 hodin denně, kromě nedělí, velikonoc, Vánoc, letnic a svátku blahoslaveného Hroznaty.
But getting to the supplier list was a real Calvary.
Ale dostat se k seznamu dodavatelů, to byla kalvárie.
Where else would I put it?
Kde ještě pampu?
People, it's a blessing in here, right?
Lidi, je tu požehnání, co?
Because Ozzak isn't here.
Protože tu není Ozzák.
Well, it's true he could scare them off a bit.
Tak je pravda, že by je mohl trošku odradit.
I found this stuck to the door when I was opening up.
Tohle jsem našla přilepené na dveřích, když jsem otvírala.
Couldn't we just get by without him for a few days?
Nemohli bychom si těch pár dní obejít bez něho.
Marcelka, his pranks are over.
Marcelko, s těmi jeho žertíky je konec.
As soon as he wakes up, I'll put a stop to it.
Jakmile se probudí, hned mu to zatrhnu.
That's not possible, but I'm worried about Zoran.
To nejde, ale mám strach o Zorana.
Did Ozzak do something to him too?
Ozzák mu taky něco provedl?
No, but he could lose his audience because of him.
Ne, ale mohl by kvůli němu přijít o tu svou audienci.
What if the Pope found out he works with such a heathen?
Co kdyby se papež dozvěděl, že pracuje s takovým neznabohem?
How would he find out?
Jak by to asi zjistil?
The Vatican is incredibly thorough.
Ve Vatikánu jsou neuvěřitelně důkladní.
The mayor, for example, lost his audience just because his city has a district called Dablice.
Primátor například přišel o tu svou audienci jenom proto, že ve svém městě trpí čtvrť, která se jmenuje Ďáblice.
Ozzak!
Ozzáku!
Simona?
Simono?
Tomas?
Tomáši?
What's going on here?
Co se to tu děje?
You tell me.
No to mi řekni ty.
Well, I come home, the door's wide open, one chair is in the hallway and you're holding the other one.
No, tak já přijdu domů, dveře dokořán, jedna židle je na chodbě a druhou ty držíš v ruce.
Right. That's...
To je viď. No to je.
Unbelievable, what's happening today.
Neuvěřitelné, co se dneska děje.
Wait, where are you going?
Počkej, kam jdeš?
I have to run.
Já musím běžet.
Wait!
Moment!
You're not going to tell me anything?
To mi jako nic neřekneš?
Sorry.
Promiň.
Bye.
Měj se.
The mayor's proposal to rename Zizkov to the Saint Ignatius district will be discussed by the council today.
Primátorův návrh přejmenovat Žižkov na čtvrť svatého Ignáce bude dnes projednávat zastupitelstvo.
What?
Cože?
Why didn't they wake me? Is it noon?
Proč mě nezbudili? Je poledne?
You've got the day off, you scare the faithful.
Máš volno, děsíš věřící.
Were you out with Ziza last night?
Ty jsi včera se Žížou?
No, why?
Ne, proč?
Nothing, nothing.
Nic, nic.
Ozzak, what did you do?
Ozzáku, co jsi provedl?
Nothing.
Nic.
It was such a blast last night at Satan.
To byla taková sranda včera u Satana.
What blast?
Jaká sranda?
We were just having a beer and suddenly some guy in a red skirt shows up and starts freaking out that the Pope is coming through tomorrow and the pub has to be shut down.
Úplně normálně jsme si dávali pivko a najednou přiletěl nějakej chlápek v červený sukni a začal vyšilovat, že zejtra pojede kolem papež a že se ta hospoda musí zavřít.
And that it's a scandal.
No a že je to skandál.
A guy in a red skirt?
Chlápek v červený sukni?
Yeah, a weirdo.
No, úchylák.
Ziza got a bit wound up and swiped his radio.
Žížu to malinko nadzvedlo a tak mu sebrala rádiovku.
Ozzak.
Ozzáku.
What?
Co je?
He started it.
On si začal.
Don't you understand that some believers might have a problem with Satan?
Copak nechápeš, že někteří věřící můžou mít se Satanem problém?
What do believers have to do with a pub?
A co mají věřící do hospody?
Jesus, what pub?
Ježíš, do jaký hospody?
The guy was a wreck.
Chlap jak starý smoklach.
He said if they close Kremenace in Liberec too, he's completely done for.
Říkal, že jestli mu zavřou i Křemenáče v Liberci, tak je úplně vyřízenej.
Hey.
Čau.
Hi, Ivuska.
Ahoj, Ivuško.
Why are there cranberries in my room?
Proč mám v pokoji klikve?
I've started clearing out.
Už jsem začal vyklízet.
We can't save the basement.
Sklep nezachráníme.
Really?
Fakt?
I visited everyone.
Pobíhal jsem všechny.
Pajerova made me sort through a trash can as a demonstration and then said she still can't vote for someone who doesn't know what biomass is.
Pajerová mě nechala ukázkově roztřídit popelnici a pak řekla, že stejně nemůže hlasovat pro někoho, kdo neví, co je to biomasa.
Damn.
Poďáku.
She's super green.
Fůl je zelená.
At Podrouzek's place there were cops and they said he won't be attending meetings for three to five years.
U Podroužka byli policajti a říkali, že na schůze nebude chodit tři až pět let.
And Vojtickova said she'd vote for us, but only if Ozzak repented.
A Vojtíčková říkala, že by pro nás hlasovala, ale jenom v případě, že by se Ozzák dal na pokání.
Which is nonsense.
Což je blbost.
Did you see that?
Viděli jste to?
That's the ultimate holy frisbee.
To je úplně boží frisbee.
I begged you on my knees to hide that somewhere.
Já jsem tě prosil na kolenou, ať to někam schováš.
What are you on about?
Co blbneš?
Tonight at Satan's we'll have a great tournament.
Večer si u Satana uděláme parádní turnaj.
What was that hat?
Co to bylo za čepku?
Please don't ask.
Prosím tě, neptej se.
Dad, it'll be fine.
Tati, to bude dobrý.
Fine?
Dobrý?
How can it be fine?
Jak to může být dobrý?
The building manager is clearly coming after us.
Správcová po nás evidentně jde.
Everyone in the building hates us.
Všechny partaje nás nesnášej.
And once Vojtickova finds out who that hat belongs to, she'll really sound the attack.
A až se Vojtíčková dozví, od koho je ta čepice, tak teprve zatroubí k útoku.
Can't Ziza just ring the doorbell?
To ta Žíža nemůže zazvonit?
Like a normal person?
Jako normální člověk?
Bro, she's not stupid.
Brácha, není blbá.
You know I switched the names on the doorbells?
Víš, že jsem přeházel jména na zvonkách?
What's going on, Marcelka?
Co se děje, Marcelko?
You called for me.
Volala jste mě.
I caught the thief.
Přistihla jsem zlodějku.
Simona?
Simono?
That's enough.
To je dost.
I was starting to think I'd have to call the police.
Už jsem myslela, že budu muset volat policajty.
Excuse me, the police should be called on you.
No dovolte, policajty se budou volat na vás.
Oh yeah, and for what?
Jo, a za co jako?
You think I'm completely stupid?
Myslíte, že já jsem úplně blbá?
She comes in saying she urgently needs a list of Johann Strauss Jr.'s operettas.
Přijde sem, že nutně potřebuje seznam operet Johanna Strausse mladšího.
And when I come back from the storeroom with the catalogue, the armchairs are gone.
A když se vrátím z kumbálu s katalogem, křesílka jsou fuč.
Armchairs.
Křesílka.
What nonsense, right?
Takovej nesmysl, viď?
It had to be her.
Musela to být ona.
The only other people in the shop were nuns.
Kromě ní byly v krámě jenom jeptišky.
Great, and she's blaming it on me.
No prosím, a hází to na mě.
Simona, this is really a bit weird, okay?
Simono, to je fakt trošku divný, jo?
First the chairs, now the armchairs.
Nejdřív ty židle, teď ty křesílka.
Well, you've really outdone yourself, you should be proud.
To jsi to teda dopracoval, to na sebe můžeš být fakt pyšnej.
What?
Co?
Accusing an unemployed mother of two small children of stealing your smelly armchairs?
Obvinit nezaměstnanou mámu dvou malých dětí z toho, že ti ukradla smradlavý křesla?
Wait, nobody's saying that.
Počkej, to přece nikdo neříká.
I'm saying it.
Já to říkám.
Fine, we'll clear it up.
Dobře, to se vysvětlí.
Simona, if you were here when the armchairs disappeared, you must have seen something.
Simono, jestli jsi tady byla, když se ty křesílka ztratily, no tak jsi přece musela něco vidět.
Well, of course I did.
No, jasně, že jo.
I saw Ozzak carrying them into the storeroom.
Viděla jsem Ozzáka, nesl je do kumbálu.
Ozzak was at home.
Ozzák byl doma.
And I was in the storeroom.
A v kumbálu jsem byla já.
Damn.
Sakra.
That's quite a mystery.
To je teda záhada.
I really don't envy you.
To vám teda nezávidím.
Well, I'm off.
Tak já jdu.
Simona, I'm not letting you go anywhere until this is cleared up.
Simono, já tě nikam nepustím, dokud se to nevysvětlí.
Sure, we'll clear it up.
No to se vysvětlí.
Let's do a reconstruction.
Uděláme rekonstrukci.
I'll go to the storeroom.
Půjdu do kumbálu.
Wait.
Moment.
But I was the one in the storeroom.
V kumbálu jsem přece byla já.
Marcelka?
Marcelko?
Yes?
Ano?
Get off me.
Slezte ze mě.
Ivo, we're saved.
Ivo, jsme zachráněni.
What's going on?
Co se děje?
Simona steals.
Simona krade.
What?
Cože?
When people find out Simona's been stealing around the building, they'll go after her and leave us alone.
Až se lidi dozví, že Simona krade po baráku, půjdou po ní a na nás se vykašlou.
What are you talking about?
O čem to mluvíš, proboha?
She stole the armchairs from the shop, so she also stole the ficus from the landing.
Ukradla křesílka v krámě, tudíž ukradla i fíkus v mezipatře.
Dad, calm down, why would she steal armchairs?
Tati, uklidni se, proč by kradla křesílka?
To pay for drugs, otherwise it doesn't make sense.
No, aby měla na drogy, jinak to nedává smysl.
That's crazy.
A to je přece šílený.
You want to rat out your friend?
Ty chceš udat svou kamarádku?
She stole armchairs.
Ukradla křesílka.
Why would she steal armchairs?
Proč by kradla křesílka?
To pay for drugs.
Aby měla na drogy.
And why would she do drugs?
A proč by brala drogy?
So it would make sense.
Aby to dávalo smysl.
Dad, please, calm down.
Tati, prosím tě, uklidni se.
At night...
V noci...
They don't sell drugs in the tunnel, and for the armchairs she wouldn't even get a straw.
V tunelu se drogy neprodávaj, ale za křesílka by si nekoupila ani brko.
Wait, I'm talking about drugs you snort.
Počkej, já mluvím o drogách, co se šňupou.
Nobody's snorting anything.
No šňupou už vůbec ne.
I have no idea what you're talking about now.
Já teď nevím, o čem mluvíš.
And honestly, I'm glad.
No já jsem vlastně ráda.
Won't you all come with me?
Nepůjdete všichni se mnou?
They closed Satan!
Zavřeli Satana!
I repeat, nobody is going to protest for some pub.
Já opakuju, že nikdo za žádnou hospodu demonstrovat nepůjde.
If I see anyone with banners, they're moving out.
Jak u někoho uvidím transparenty, stěhuje se.
So we're just supposed to take this, bro?
A to si to jako brácha máme nechat líbit?
Because of some Pope they shut down the last good pub in Prague.
Kvůli nějakému pápežovi zavřeli tu poslední dobrou hospodu v Praze.
How do you know it's because of the Pope?
Jak víš, že kvůli papežovi?
Some weirdo in a red skirt showed up there yesterday.
Včera tam přiletěl nějakej úchyl v červený sukni.
Cardinal Bursik.
Kardinál Bursík.
And today the health inspectors show up, coincidence?
A dneska náhodou přijde hygiena, co?
Bro, even the biggest idiot can put two and two together.
Brácha, to si musí dát dohromady i ta největší trubka.
Let's go.
A jdeme.
Nowhere.
Nikam.
And you still dare to show your face after all that.
A ty si ještě po tom všem troufáš chodit na oči.
Oh.
Aha.
And I thought you'd like to see your armchairs.
A já jsem myslela, že bys rád viděl svoje křesílka.
Where?
Kde?
I smell beer.
Cítím pivo.
Simona, I swear, if you yell "watch out, monitor lizard" now, we are done for good, got it?
Teda Simono, jestli teďka zařveš bacha varan, tak je mezi náma definitivní konec, jasný?
You're stunned, huh?
To čumíte, co?
What is this?
Co to je?
A pub! Satan Around the Corner, bro!
Hospoda U Satana za rohem, brácha!
A pub?
Hospoda?
This is a bunker?
To je kryt?
Well, if there's a war, we're screwed.
No až bude válka, tak máme po ptákách.
But until then, Horvath's brother at the ministry will cover it up.
Ale do té doby to tady Horváthů brácha na ministerstvu pokryje.
Sure.
Jasně.
There's going to be trouble.
Z toho bude průser.
You've always been a coward.
A ty jsi byl vždycky poseroutka.
Excuse me?
No dovol?
You are, that's why I didn't tell you.
Byl, proto jsem ti taky nic neřekla.
But the thing is, thanks to you Ozzak doesn't want to settle anything with the Pope anymore.
Ale je fakt, že díky tobě si teď Ozzák nechce s papežem nic vyříkávat.
Me? No way.
Já? Kdeže.
One more and I'm going.
A ještě jednu a jdu.
And if not me, then Ziza will get revenge for all of us.
A když ne já, tak Žíža se pomstí za nás za všecky.
How can you possibly think you can just open a pub without a permit?
A jak si vůbec můžeš myslet, že si takhle otevřeš hospodu bez povolení?
But with my armchairs.
Ale s mýma křesílkama.
I'll return them once this gets going.
Ty vrátím, až se toto trochu zavede.
Tomorrow!
Zítra!
I actually applied for a permit, but they'd only give it to me if I had a cook-waiter qualification or a relative with one.
Náhodou jsem o povolení žádala, ale dali by mi ho jenom, kdybych měla obor kuchař číšník nebo příbuznej.
And I've got asphalt worker-insulator.
A já mám asfalter izolatér.
What am I actually drinking?
Co to vlastně piju?
Mojito.
Mojito.
That's what you wanted.
Vždyť jsi to chtěl.
Where's the mint?
Kde je máta?
Mint?
Máta?
Aren't you fancy.
Jsi nějaká fajnovka.
There's green, beer and ficus.
Zelená, pivo a fíkus.
Just like from Fidel.
Ale jak od Fidela.
Fidl.
Fídl.
The building manager.
Správcová.
And now we see the mayor walking alongside the popemobile.
A nyní vidíme primátora, který kráčí vedle papamobilu.
He's flagellating himself and gazing meaningfully at the Holy Father.
Bičuje se a významně hledí na svatého otce.
The Pope, however, is looking the other way.
Papež se ovšem dívá jinam.
Still, if Mr. Ozzak had tackled the Pope, we'd be learning about him in school.
Stejně, kdyby pan Ozzák skolil papeže, tak bychom se pak o něm učili ve škole.
I don't know where they were, but they came back with Dad so wasted they couldn't even tip over a trash can.
Já nevím, kde byli, ale vrátili se s tátou tak zmatení, že by nesklopili ani popelnici.
How is this going to end?
Jak tohle dopadne?
If the building manager sees them in this state, we'll lose not only the basement but also the keys to the attic.
Jestli je správcová v tomhle stavu uvidí, tak přijdeme nejen o sklep, ale i o klíče od půdy.
And I'll be stuck with cranberries in my room for the rest of my life.
A já budu s klikvema v pokoji do konce života.
You have cranberries?
Ty máš klikve?
A whole room full.
Plnej pokoj.
Lucky you.
Ty se máš.
I'm never getting married.
To já se nikdy nevdám.
Fellow club member!
Kolega ze spolku!
Ivuska?
Ivuško?
Don't you want to ask me something?
Nechceš se mě náhodou na něco zeptat?
Why are you sitting next to the couch?
Proč si sedáš vedle kanape?
But you don't want to ask me anything else.
Ale nic jinýho se mě už nechceš zeptat.
How did the meeting go?
Jak dopadla schůze?
Right question.
Správná otázka.
It couldn't have gone better.
Lepší už to být nemohlo.
Really?
Jo?
What did the building manager say?
Co říkala správcová?
Nothing.
Nic.
She didn't even show up, sweetheart.
Vůbec nepřišla, bobo.
For the first time in the history of the meetings.
Poprvé v dějinách schůzí.
Is that possible?
Je to možné?
Nobody knows.
To nikdo neví.
But it might have something to do with the fact that two hooligans piled so many trash cans in front of her door that she couldn't get out of her apartment at all.
Ale mohlo by to souviset s tím, že nějací dva chuligáni jí naskládali přede dveře tolik popelnic, že se vůbec nemohla dostat z bytu ven.
Poor thing, nobody heard her.
Bohužel, chudák, nikdo ji neslyšel.
Just two hooligans?
Jenom ty dva chuligáni?
But they weren't hooligans.
No ale to nebyli chuligáni.
They saved the basement, didn't they?
Zachránili přece sklep?
They were heroes.
To byli hrdinové.
Good evening.
Dobrý večer.
I'm very sorry to bother you at such an ungodly hour, but...
Moc se omlouvám, že ruším v tak nekřesťanskou hodinu, ale...
That's alright.
To je v pořádku.
Thank you.
Děkuju.
It's about Jarmila, the building manager.
Jde o Jarmilu, tedy paní správcovou.
Someone barricaded her in her apartment.
Někdo ji zabarikádoval v bytě.
I can't lift those trash cans.
Já ty popelnice neunesu.
I've already been to every apartment, but nobody opened.
Už jsem obešla všechny partaje, ale nikdo mi neotevřel.
Sure.
Jasně.
Dad's probably not here, but my uncle will definitely help you.
Táta tady asi není, ale strejda vám určitě pomůže.
Of course.
No jasně.
And I've been at the trash cans.
A jdu od popelnic.
Actually, I'd rather not bother you.
Teď mě napadá, že radši nebudu obtěžovat.
We'll manage with Jarmilka somehow.
My to asi s Jarmilkou nějak zvládneme.
Don't be silly, you can't haul those by yourself.
Ale to neblázněte, přeci to nebudete tahat sama.
He'll be glad to help.
On vám rád pomůže.
He's the one who needs the most help, Ivuska.
On je ten, co potřebuje nejvíc pomoci, Ivuško.
You see, his heart...
Vždyť jeho srdce...
...has been taken over by Satan.
...ovládl Satan.
It was acting up.
Vyvádělo.
Apparently Satan is finished.
Prý u Satana je konec.
It's...
Je...
Hosanna.
Hosana.
The pub.
Hospoda.
We'll all help you.
Pomůžem vám všichni.
Let's go.
Jdem.
From here I can't quite tell what's happening.
No odsud nevím přesně, co se děje.
It looks as if the popemobile's path has been blocked by some kind of...
Jako by papamobilu zablokovalo cestu nějaké...
Well, it appears to be a sewage truck with a chalice painted on the side.
No vypadá to jako fekální vůz s kalichem namalovaným na boku.
That's Ziza.
No to je Žíža.